# BEN HASSINE MOHAMED DHIA Nabeul, Tunisia bhmeddhiaa Backend Developer Dhiabenhassine benhassine.med.dhia@gmail.com 00216 90 117 343 Version Français

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

With years of experience as a developer, i'm driven by a continual love of leaning and innovation. My career is marked by collaborative efforts to develop web-based applications and improve product quality through code optimisation and proactive problem-solving

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance

### **Full-Stack Developer**

12-2024 - Present

-Frontend Development:

- Develop the Fantasy Tunisia mobile application using React Natives for crossplatform compatibility (iOS and Android).
- Design and develop a high-performance, user-friendly mobile application using React Natives.

-Backend Development:

- Develop and maintain a scalable backend using GoLang.
- Implement RESTful APIs to handle user data, team management, and real-time
- Ensure secure and efficient data handling with Supabase. -Integration:
- Integrate frontend and backend components effectively to deliver a cohesive
- Work with third-party APIs and libraries to enhance the application's functionality. Address and resolve application issues promptly.

**Technologies used:** 



### **Backend Developer**

08-2024 - 11-2024

**Digital Natives** 

- Designed and developed RESTful APIs to handle requests and responses efficiently.
- Designed and maintained relational database schemas in MySQL.
- Used tools like APIDOG.com for documenting APIs.
- Performed unit tests on the server using Termius.

#### Kuda Website **Technologies used:**

NodeJS Express

JavaScript

### **Project Manager**

12-2023 - 08-2024

**Digital Natives** 

- Defining Project Scope: Work closely with founders and stakeholders to define project goals, deliverables, timelines, and success criteria.
- Sprint Planning: Lead sprint planning sessions, ensuring that the team has clear, actionable tasks and understands priorities.
- Iteration Reviews and Retrospectives: Conduct regular reviews and retrospectives to evaluate progress, gather feedback, and continuously improve processes.
- Team Collaboration: Facilitate collaboration between development, design, marketing, and sales to ensure that project goals are met cohesively.

# Digital Natives Web Site

# **Full-Stack Developer**

02-2023 - 11-2023

**Digital Natives** 

 Develop the backend for a web application similar to Airbnb using Node.js, Express.js and Sequelize. Imple- ment APIs such as OpenAI and FastForex.

- Perform unit tests on the server using Termius.
- · Document the project using APIDOG.com.
- Develop an admin dashboard with a Material UI template.

# superhost.com.tn

**Technologies used:** 











# Freelance

08-2022 - 10-2023

RebootKamp (RBK)

Project 1: Sales Store Dashboard Full-Stack Developer

- Develop the backend for an Admin dashboard using Node.js, Express.js, and Sequelize.
- Develop an admin dashboard with a Material UI template.

# **Technologies used:**

Project 2: Tawelti Full-Stack Developer

- Integrate cloudinary with react Natives and Google maps.
- · Develop the backend for the mobile application using Node.js, Express.js, and Sequelize.
- Designed and devoloped an admin dashboard.
- · Colaborate on data analisis and improve SQL queries of high volume databases.

# **Technologies used:**

# Full-Stack Developer

06-2020 - 08-2022

PROMOCUISINE (Cuisina + Marmotek)

#### • Displays key sales metrics such as total sales, number of deals closed, and topperforming products.

• Shows the top-performing sales representatives based on various criteria. A section to manage the list of products/services, including details like pricing and

# **Technologies used:**

description.

JavaScript React

### **LANGUAGE**

**French** 

Fluent **English** 

Fluent

**Arabic** 

Natives Language

### **EDUCATION**

### **Full Stack Javascript** Developer

RebootKamp (RBK) Aougst 2022 - Feb 2023

### Master degree in quality, safety and environment

management Leaders University -Tunisia Sep 2014 - Oct 2016

# License in international

economics and finance Faculty of economics and management - Tunisia Sep 2010 - June 2013

### **Baccalaureate**

High school 7 November-Tunisia Sep 2009 - Juin 2010

### DEVELOPMENT STACK

## **Programming Languages**

GoLang Python

**TypeScript** 

JavaScript

**Frontend Libraries &** Frameworks

React Natives / React

Next.js

**Backend Frameworks &** 

Node JS

**Databases** 

Express JS MYSQL, Sequelize

SupaBase

MongoDB

### Others Git Unlayer

phpMyAdmin ApiDog Docker Redux

# **SKILLS**

Problem-solving Team Work Communication skills

Creativity Client Interaction

Documentaion **Project Management**